<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="0141ABA8-0E42-411F-9EA6-6930390AFE7C">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20260316" date="2026-03-16 14:19:13 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Version 2.1.0 is out</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText> revised semantics and syntax for handling arrays in rules. For arrays, pattern matching and updates now only operate on individual items. For example, the following rule doubles the value of the second item of array [t] :&#xD;	     | (..., t[1]:v, ...) -&gt; (..., t[1]:v*2, ...)&#xD;Array indexes in this context may be constants, local variables or any arithmetic combination of these. &#xD;A typical example is given is examples/working/histo[lf].&#xD;As a consequence array comprehension expressions, such as&#xD;	     | ... -&gt; (..., t:[i+1 | i=0 to 4], ...)&#xD;are no longer valid in rule RHS.&#xD;This is not a problem in practice since their translation in VHDL was relying on the ability to perform multiple concurrent memory updates, not always supported by synthetizers.&#xD;Array comprehension expressions are still supported for initializing arrays (at declaration), however.&#xD;Sec 2.2.2, 2.4.4 and Chap. 3 of the reference manual have been updated according to this modification.&#xD;&#xD; added a new FIFO model to the VHDL library (credits: F.Berry, &lt;a href="mailto:francois.berry@univ-bpclermont.fr"&gt;francois.berry@univ-bpclermont.fr&lt;/a&gt;). This model supports automatic switching from a LE to a RAM based implementation. The previous models (fifo_small and fifo_big are still available with the [-vhdl_small_fifo_model] and [-vhdl_default_big_fifo_model] options (see Sec 9.5 of the reference manual)&#xD;&#xD; the compiler now detects redefinitions in type, actor, value and io declarations; it also detects when, within an actor, a variable declaration shadows an input, output or parameter. &#xD;&#xD; added an option [-dump_fsms] to dump graphical representation of "stateful" actors.&#xD;A "stateful" actor is an actor for which the set of transition rules involves at least one local variable having an enumerated type. Ex:&#xD;	     actor a (...)&#xD;	       var s: {S0,S1,...} = S0&#xD;	     rules&#xD;	       (s:S0, ...) -&gt; (s:S1, ...)&#xD;In this case the enumerated variable is interpreted as a "state" variable and the set of transition rules is interpreted as describing a state diagram. The graphical representation of this diagram is output in [.dot] format (for visualisation with the Graphviz (&lt;a href="http://www.graphviz.org"&gt;http://www.graphviz.org&lt;/a&gt;) suite of tools.&#xD;The name of is file is &lt;actor_name&gt;_fsm.dot. &#xD;Illustrative examples are given in [examples/working/suml] and [examples/working/histof].&#xD;&#xD; integer constants are now printed without signness indication (S/U) by default. To get this back, use the option [-show_signness]</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;25/04/2014&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
